one day in miss hazel's classroom
有一天在Hazel老师的教室里
something different was introduced
引入了一些不同的东西
with a warm smile
带着温暖的微笑
she pointed to the board and said  this week
她指着板子说这周
we're doing a group project
我们在做一个小组项目
it's called me myself
它叫我自己
each group should create something that
每个小组都应该创造一些东西
shows what emotions they often feel
表现出他们经常感受到的情绪
what they need
他们需要什么
and what they do when those feelings show up  basically
以及当这些感觉出现时他们会做什么
how they manage them  oh  i know
他们是如何管理他们的，哦，我知道。
it's about happy
是关于快乐的
sad stuff like that
像这样悲伤的事情
i'm not really sure how i manage my feelings
我不知道该怎么控制自己的感情
feelings are like different colors
感情就像不同的颜色
each one has something to say
每个人都有话要说
but before we paint with any color
但在我们用任何颜色作画之前
we need to know exactly what we're doing
我们需要知道我们到底在做什么
Felix the curious fox felt a little confused
好奇的狐狸菲利克斯感到有点困惑
he was used to researching space and plants
他习惯于研究太空和植物
but now he had to write about himself
但现在他不得不写自己
about emotions and needs
关于情感和需求
he had no idea where to start
他不知道从哪里开始
菲利克斯was grouped with Luna and Milo
菲利克斯 was grouped with Luna and Milo
on the way home
在回家的路上
he told his mom  mom
他告诉他妈妈妈妈
we have to do a project about our feelings
我们要做一个关于我们感情的项目
how we manage them and what we need
我们如何管理它们以及我们需要什么
but i don't even know what
但我甚至不知道是什么
feelings i have most or what i need
我最有的感觉或我需要的东西
oh  honey
噢亲爱的
that's not hard
这并不难
you always figure things out
你总是把事情搞清楚
Felix didn't respond
Felix没反应
he felt like she wasn't taking him seriously
他觉得她没把他当回事
later at home
后来在家
he talked to his older brother
他和他哥哥谈过了
his brother laughed and said
他哥哥笑着说
you still don't know how you feel
你还是不知道自己的感受
do you even know anything
你知道什么吗？
you're always making fun of me
你总是取笑我
i know i don't know everything
我知道我不是什么都知道
but mocking me doesn't help
但嘲笑我也于事无补
if you won't help
如果你不帮忙
then just say nothing
那就什么都不说
he stormed out of the room
他冲出房间
they didn't talk again that night
那天晚上他们再没说过话
the next day during recess
第二天休息时
Felix sat with Oliver and Toby and said
菲利克斯坐在奥利弗和托比旁边说
i feel confused
我感到困惑
i don't know what our project is even supposed to be
我甚至不知道我们的项目应该是什么
i asked my mom and brother
我问了我妈妈和哥哥
but they didn't take me seriously
但他们没把我当回事
i think we often act based on how we feel
我认为我们通常会根据自己的感觉来行动
because our needs and requests come from our feelings
因为我们的需求和要求来自我们的感受
sometimes i don't even know what i feel
有时我甚至不知道自己的感受
that's why i keep a notebook where
这就是为什么我有一个笔记本
i write down what happened  how i feel
我写下发生的事情我的感受
what i need
我所需要的
and what i want to ask
还有我想问的
i know every feeling matters and we shouldn't ignore them
我知道每一种感觉都很重要，我们不应该忽视它们
but it's also important not to let
但同样重要的是不要让
feelings make all our decisions
感觉决定了我们的一切
i always try to stop and ask
我总是试着停下来问
where did this feeling come from
这种感觉从何而来
then i decide what to do
然后我决定该怎么做
Felix thought for a moment and said
菲利克斯想了想说
i understand feelings
我理解感情
i know they matter
我知道他们很重要
but i don't get how they can be important and
但我不明白它们怎么会很重要
still not be the ones making decisions for us
仍然不是为我们做决定的人
so  what else do we need to make decisions  just then
那么我们还需要做什么决定呢？
the bell rang
铃响了
and the teacher called everyone back inside
老师把所有人都叫了进去
in class  Felix  Luna and Milo worked on their project
在课堂上Felix Luna和Milo在做他们的项目
i want to draw pictures of how feelings show up in my body
我想画出感觉是如何在我身体里显现的
i might write about what helps me calm down when i'm upset
我可能会写些什么能让我在心烦意乱时冷静下来
suddenly  Milo frowned and snapped
突然米洛皱起眉头，厉声说道
ick  this stuff won't make our project great
讨厌这些东西不会让我们的项目变得伟大
i want it to be excellent
我希望它很棒。
not filled with silly feelings and drawings
没有充满愚蠢的感觉和图画
everyone went quiet
所有人都安静下来
Felix wanted to say something  but didn't  he thought
Felix想说点什么但他没想到
i'm angry  but what's the right thing to do
我很生气，但该怎么办？
should i argue with Milo  stay quiet
我应该和米洛争论吗？保持安静。
fake a smile
假笑
at that moment
在那一刻
Luna took a deep breath and calmly said
露娜深吸一口气，平静的说道
Milo  i get that you might be worried the
Milo我知道你可能担心
project won't turn out well
项目不会有好结果
but being upset doesn't mean you
但心烦意乱并不意味着你
should talk to us like that
应该那样跟我们说话
if you're worried
如果你担心的话
we're here to listen
我们是来听的
mylo didn't frown anymore
Mylo不再皱眉了
he just looked down
他只是往下看
after that moment
在那一刻之后
the group was quieter
这群人更安静了
yulix thought
Yulix认为
i was upset by milo's words
Milo的话让我很难过
but i didn't say anything
但我什么都没说
i just thought about it
我只是想了想
does that mean i managed my feeling or just swallowed it
这是否意味着我控制了自己的感觉，还是只是吞下了它？
what's the difference anyway
反正有什么区别
during the next break
在接下来的休息时间
Felix approached miss Hazel and hesitantly asked
菲利克斯走近黑兹尔小姐，犹豫地问
miss Hazel  i have a question
Hazel小姐我有个问题
you said our feelings are important
你说我们的感情很重要
but what if a strong feeling shows up
但是如果一种强烈的感觉出现了呢？
and we don't want to act badly
我们不想表现得不好
what should we do  like today
我们应该像今天这样做什么
a classmate upset me
一个同学让我心烦
but i stayed quiet
但我保持沉默
does that mean i managed my feeling
这是否意味着我控制了自己的感觉？
or just shut myself down
或者只是关闭自己
miss Hazel smiled kindly and said
Hazel小姐和蔼地笑着说
managing feelings means that before we act
管理感情意味着在我们行动之前
we take a moment to look at what we're feeling
我们花点时间看看我们的感受
sometimes staying quiet isn't just silence
有时候保持沉默不仅仅是沉默
it matters that you notice what you
重要的是你注意到你
felt and then chose your reaction
感受然后选择你的反应
managing a feeling means making a little
控制一种感觉意味着做一点
pause between emotion and reaction
情绪和反应之间的停顿
that pause helps us make better choices
这种停顿有助于我们做出更好的选择
we can understand our emotions
我们可以理解自己的情绪
but not let them control us
但不能让他们控制我们
feelings come like waves
感情如波浪般涌来
and you can choose what to do with that wave
你可以选择如何处理这个波浪。
miss Hazel  so
Hazel小姐所以
when i stayed quiet today
当我今天保持沉默时
was that the right decision
这是正确的决定吗？
how do i know my choice was smart
我怎么知道我的选择是明智的？
not just bottling things up
不仅仅是把事情藏起来
there's not always just one right decision
并不总是只有一个正确的决定
the right choice is one where you feel you
正确的选择是让你感觉到你
respected yourself and didn't hurt others
尊重自己，不伤害别人
not pretending nothing happened and not shouting either
不要假装什么都没发生，也不要大喊大叫
it's that space in between where you see
你看到的是两者之间的空间
your feeling and think it through
你的感觉和思考
there's a helpful tool i call the five golden questions
有一个有用的工具，我称之为五个黄金问题
once you feel something
一旦你感觉到什么
ask yourself these  1
问问自己这1
what exactly am i feeling right now  sad  angry  worried
我现在到底是什么感觉？悲伤、愤怒、担心
upset
心烦意乱
what caused this feeling
是什么导致了这种感觉
what happened
发生了什么事
who said or did what
谁说或做了什么
three  if i react quickly
如果我反应快就三个
what could happen
会发生什么
would someone get hurt
有人会受伤吗？
will i feel better or worse after
之后我会感觉更好还是更糟？
four  what are some things i could do
四，我能做些什么？
take a deep breath
深呼吸
find a quiet space
找一个安静的空间
talk to someone
与某人交谈
speak up calmly
平静地说出来
five  which choice helps me respect myself and others
五种选择有助于我尊重自己和他人
miss Hazel smiled and said
Hazel小姐笑着说
that last one is really important
最后一个真的很重要
figuring out what helps you stay calm
想办法让你保持冷静
and still feel OK about yourself
仍然对自己感觉良好
Felix thought about it
Felix想过了
can you give me an example
你能给我举个例子吗？
let's say someone treats me badly
假设有人对我不好
i don't stay silent if it keeps happening
如果它一直发生，我不会保持沉默
that's respecting myself
那是尊重我自己
but i also don't shout or hurt them back
但我也不会大喊大叫或伤害他们
that's respecting others
那是尊重别人
so
所以
if i didn't tell my classmate not to talk to me like that
如果我不告诉我的同学不要这样和我说话
i didn't respect myself
我没有尊重自己
sometimes  silence is a way to take care of yourself
有时候沉默是照顾自己的一种方式
but if you still feel hurt or ignored
但如果你仍然感到受伤或被忽视
maybe it's time to try a different way
也许是时候换个方法了
like calmly saying
就像平静地说
i don't like being spoken to that way
我不喜欢别人这么跟我说话
that's healthy boundaries
这是健康的界限
it means you didn't ignore your feelings
说明你没有忽视自己的感受
and you didn't disrespect the other person either
你也没有不尊重对方
Felix thanked miss Hazel
Felix感谢Hazel小姐
she reminded him
她提醒他
managing emotions takes practice  always
控制情绪总是需要练习的
on presentation day
在演示日
Luna shared her drawings about where
露娜分享了她画的
feelings show up in her body
感觉在她身体里显现出来
Milo read a few lines about his anxiety
Milo读了几行关于他的焦虑
that the project wouldn't turn out great
这个项目不会有好结果
and Felix said
费利克斯说
i learned in this project that having feelings is important
我在这个项目中学到了感受很重要
but we shouldn't let feelings alone make all our choices
但是我们不应该让感情独自做我们所有的选择
now i understand more about noticing my emotions
现在我更懂得注意自己的情绪了
and making thoughtful respectful decisions
并做出深思熟虑的尊重决定
you've all grown
你们都长大了
feelings will always be part of us
感情永远是我们的一部分
but when we face them with care and thought
但当我们用心去面对他们
we become stronger
我们变得更强大
managing emotions means you don't have to
控制情绪意味着你不必
react right away when a feeling shows up
当感觉出现时立即做出反应
you can pause
你可以暂停
talk to yourself kindly
亲切地自言自语
and choose what helps you stay calm and respectful
选择能让你保持冷静和尊重的东西
and remember
并记住
the me myself project isn't over
我自己的项目还没有结束
it's just beginning
这才刚刚开始
keep talking about what you've learned
继续谈论你学到的东西
and don't forget to talk to Felix
别忘了和费利克斯谈谈
i think he's got some golden tips to share
我想他有一些黄金秘诀要分享